alice-in-wonderland.net 2019-06-09

# Terms, conditions, cookies and privacy - Alice-in-Wonderland.net

## 1\. Webshop terms and conditions

Alice-in-Wonderland.net is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com.

This means I have teamed up with Amazon.com to be able to offer you a broad selection of Alice in Wonderland related items, combined with secure ordering and great service. When you buy a product from my shop, you make a purchase agreement with Amazon.com or one of its third party sellers. Amazon.com and its third party sellers will handle all aspects of your order; I have no items in stock and do not ship anything myself. Please read the [service page](http://www.alice-in-wonderland.net/shop/customer-service/) for more information.

Certain content that appears in the webshop, like manufacturer product descriptions, product details and customer reviews, comes from Amazon Services LLC. This content is provided ‘as is’ and is subject to change or removal at any time. Product prices and availability are accurate as of the date/time indicated and are subject to change. The product information and pricing on the Amazon.com website is leading. My own descriptions and prices may be incorrect or outdated, as Amazon.com or the third party seller may change it after I have added the item to my shop. Any price and availability information displayed on Amazon.com at the time of purchase will apply to the purchase of the product.

The Amazon Associates logo is a trademark of Amazon.com, Inc.

## 2\. Reviews on the blog

Sometimes I review products on my blog. I may have purchased those myself, or I may have gotten them for free from the manufacturer/shop/publisher (whether or not on my own request) for reviewing purposes. Regardless of whether I paid for them, I will always give my own and honest opinion about them. I do not review everything that is offered to me – I make my own picks and I never guarantee positive reviews.

## 3\. Cookies and personal data storage

Several plugins that I use for my website may collect personal data like IP-addresses. Also, you can choose to send personal data using fill-out forms on this site (for example, when commenting on a blog post or making a post on the forum). This website also makes use of cookies. A cookie is a small file that is sent with web pages and stored by your browser on the hard drive of your computer. With these cookies I try to improve my (future) service and your user experience when you visit my site.

When necessary for keeping this site safe and secure, some personal data (like your IP address) will be stored without your explicit permission. Functional cookies (cookies that are necessary to make the website operate) and analytical cookies that have no impact on your privacy, will always be placed when you visit this website. You have a choice whether or not to accept the use of other types of cookies (like 3rd party cookies for social media or advertising). You can make this choice using the bar at the bottom of the website. If you do not click on the accept or decline button but continue to use this site by clicking to other pages, this action is considered to be an acceptance.  
If you want to change your choice, see the button in the paragraph ‘Manage cookies, advertisements and personal data’ at the bottom of this page.

Below you can read more about the cookies set by web pages on this website and when your personal data is stored.

### Cookiebar

The cookiebar offers you the choice to accept or decline cookies other than functional and analytical cookies. I am legally obliged to prove whether or not you have given permission for this. Therefore, this cookiebar plugin will store your IP-adress together with your choice. The cookie that remembers your choice will expire after one year.

### Blog

For my site and blog, I use WordPress. If you leave a comment on a blogpost you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in functional cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you leave a comment on the blog, your name, IP address, email address, and browser user agent string will be stored in my websites database, together with your comment. This is necessary to help spam detection. Only your name is visible to other visitors; only I can view all details. An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available [here](https://automattic.com/privacy/). If you have a Gravatar / profile picture, it will be visible to the public in the context of your comment. If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so I can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue. Your comment is checked by Akismet Anti-Spam, an automated spam detection service. You can read their privacy policy [here](https://automattic.com/privacy-notice/).

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if you have visited the other website. These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website. For more information about what cookies these websites place and what they do with your (personal) data they process through these cookies, please refer to their own privacy statements. I have no influence on this.

  * [YouTube](http://www.google.com/intl/nl/policies/privacy/) (Google) privacy policy 

### Forum

My phpBB forum uses cookies to make the forum function. They are used to remember whether you are logged in, whether you already voted in a poll, etc. No personal information is being gathered and stored by the forum, unless you make a post or explicitly submit personal information yourself via a form (like the registration form and profile form).

It is not necessary to create an account to use the forum. When you make a guest post, your IP address and username is being stored in the database, together with the contents of your comment. You are not required to fill out your real name als a username. Your IP address is being stored to prevent abuse: I need it to be able to ban spammers.

When you choose to create a user account and/or user profile, you agree that all data you submit is stored in the forum’s database, together with your IP address.

### Webshop

My webshop uses the WooCommerce plugin, which sets three cookies. The first two cookies contain information about the shopping cart as a whole and help WooCommerce know when the cart data changes. The third cookie contains a unique code for each customer so that it knows where to find the cart data in the database for each customer. No personal information is stored within these cookies.

Alice-in-wonderland.net does not store personal information from webshop customers. After you click the check out button, you are being taken to the Amazon.com website where you can enter your personal details and finalize your order. Amazon is responsible for processing and protecting the personal data you provide when making a purchase.

### Social media

This website includes social media buttons. The Facebook share, Twitter, and Pinterest buttons allow you to share my web pages via these social networks. If you click on them, a window will open and load the platform’s share option. These platforms may then place cookies according to their own policies. If you do not want this, just don’t use the share buttons.

For more information about what cookies these social media platforms place and what they do with your (personal) data they process through these cookies, please refer to their own privacy statements. I have no influence on this.

### Google Analytics

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (Google). I use this service to track how visitors use the website, with the aim to improve the website.

The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google uses this information to track how you use the website, to compile reports on website activity for website operators and to provide other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Analytics data that is associated with cookies, user identifiers, or advertising identifiers is being stored for 50 months.

I have signed a data processing amendment with Google, which states that Google acts only as a processor in the processing of the personal data of my website visitors. Google may disclose the information to third parties if Google is legally required, or if third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. I have no influence on this.

I will never (and will not allow any third party to) use the statistical analytics tool to track or to collect any personally identifiable information of visitors to my site. Only part of your IP address is being sent to Google (the last octet is masked). Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. Neither I nor Google will link, or seek to link, an IP address with the identity of a computer user.

### DoubleClick

If you allow all cookies on this site, in addition to the standard Google Analytics cookies to track use of the website, an additional “third party” cookie is placed by DoubleClick.

Using this cookie, Google Analytics reports with interest and demographic data of website visitors will be generated.

In addition, I will have the opportunity to use the display advertising features of Google Analytics, such as remarketing, integration of the DoubleClick platform and generating reports for Google Display Network impressions. This allows me amongst others to tailor my advertisements to your click behaviour during your previous visits to my website.

### Hotjar

If you have allowed all cookies on this site, a tool called Hotjar may collect data from your visit. It may among others record your mouse movements and scrolling behaviour. I use this data to analyse how visitors use my website, in order to improve the user experience.

Site visitors are assigned a unique user identifier, so that Hotjar can keep track of returning visitors without relying on any personal information, such as the IP address. The last octet of IP addresses of visitors are set to 0, to ensure your full IP address is never stored.  
When collecting data with recordings, Hotjar automatically suppresses keystroke data on password fields and other sensitive fields.

You can read all details about your data safety, privacy and security [on the Hotjar website](https://help.hotjar.com/hc/en-us/articles/115011639887-Data-Safety-Privacy-Security). You can also read about [the cookies they store on your computer](https://help.hotjar.com/hc/en-us/articles/115011789248-Hotjar-Cookies).

### Security plugins

To secure my site, I use plugins like Wordfence and Sucuri Security. These plugins store your IP-address and location. This is necessary to identify spammers and hackers and thereby keep this website safe.

### Backups

My webhost creates regular backups of my website and databases, as does the plugin Updraft Plus.

I have signed a data processing amendment with A2hosting, which states that A2hosting acts only as a processor in the processing of the personal data of my website visitors. Read about my webhosts privacy and security polity [here](https://www.a2hosting.com/about/policies#Privacy-Policy).

Updraft Plus backups are stored for a maximum of 3 weeks in my Google Drive account, to which only I have access. Google stores this data in secured data centers. Google will not share these files and data with others except as described in their privacy policy. You can read the Google Drive’s Terms of Service [here](https://support.google.com/drive/answer/2450387?hl=en).

## Manage cookies, advertisements and personal data

You can use the ‘[Ad Settings](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/?hl=nl)‘ option to manage the Google ads you see and to opt out of interest-based ads.

You can also use the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) to ensure that Google Analytics cannot use your data.

You can also manage the cookies from many companies, that use these for online advertising, on the page [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/nl/uw-advertentie-voorkeuren).

Finally, you can [manage cookies in your web browser](http://www.google.nl/intl/nl/policies/technologies/managing/).

If you have used the cookie bar on this website to accept or decline all types of cookies, you can click the button below to change your choice.  

If you want to review your personal data or want your personal data to be removed from my databases under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) law, you can [send me a request](mailto:lenny@alice-in-wonderland.net). This does not include any data I am obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## 4\. Company info and contact details

I am not a registered business, this is my private website which I operate as a hobby. My name is Lenny de Rooy, I live in the Netherlands and you can contact me through email: [lenny@alice-in-wonderland.net](mailto:lenny@alice-in-wonderland.net).
